M.L. Calk Civil War Letters, 1861-1863
University of Houston Libraries
M.L. Calk Civil War Letters
December 1861-May 1863
Caulk, Martin L.
1969-008
The M.L. Calk collection consists of eight letters that M.L. Calk wrote while he served with the 23rd Alabama Volunteer Infantry Regiment. M.L. Calk served with the 23rd Alabama Volunteer Infantry Regiment in both the Kentucky (September - October 1862) and Vicksburg (December 1862 - July 1863) Campaigns.
1 box, 8 items; 0.25 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Biographical Note
Martin L. Calk was a member of the 23rd Alabama Volunteer Infantry Regiment of the Confederate Army. This regiment was formed under the command of Colonel Franklin K. Beck on November 19, 1861 at Camp Wilcox, near Montgomery, Alabama. M.L. Calk served with the 23rd Alabama Volunteer Infantry Regiment in both the Kentucky (September - October 1862) and Vicksburg (December 1862 - July 1863) Campaigns.
Scope and Contents
The M.L. Calk collection consists of eight letters that M.L. Calk wrote while he served with the 23rd Alabama Volunteer Infantry Regiment. Four of the letters are addressed to his mother, W.E. Calk, and four are addressed to his sister, Emma A. Calk. These handwritten letters, dating from December 9, 1861 through May 8, 1863, are accompanied by typed transcriptions. Several letters have additional writing in another hand.
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Index Terms
Terms are either Library of Congress Subject Headings or taken from local sources.
Subjects (Persons)
Calk, M.L.
Subjects
Confederate States of America. Army. Alabama Infantry Regiment, 23rd; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives, Confederate.; Alabama -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Social aspects.; Alabama -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Social aspects.
Formats
Correspondence
Sources
“Campaigns and Battles of the Twenty-third Alabama Volunteer Infantry Regiment C.S.A.” The Civil War Home Page. http://members.aol.com/armyoftenn/23 ala inf/23-c b.htm (23 March 2000)
Canerossi, Stephen R. “Twenty-third Alabama Volunteer Infantry Regiment Regimental History - Part One.” The Civil War Home Page. 1995. http://members.aol.com/armyoftenn/23 ala inf/23-part1.htm (23 March 2000)
Detailed Description
  - Calk, M.L. ALS. Mobile, Ala. December 9, 1861. To E.A. Calk. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - With AN. n.p.undated To Martin [Calk]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Calk, M.L. ALS. Knoxville, Tenn. March 11, 1862. To W.E. Calk. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Calk, M.L. ALS. Jackson County, Ala. April 12, 1862. To E.A. Calk. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Calk, M.L. ALS. n.p. May 20, 1862. To E.A. Calk. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Calk, M.L. ALS. Knoxville, Tenn. June 22, 1862. To W.E. Calk. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Calk, M.L. ALS. Camp near Blanes Cross Roads. July 16, 1862. To W.E. Calk. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Calk, M.L. ALS. Camp Chas, Vicksburg, Miss. February 15, 1863. To W.E. Calk. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Calk, M.L. ALS. Camp near Vicksburg, Miss. May 8, 1863. To E.A. Calk. (Box 1, Folder 8)